<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ALMA | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/alma/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/alma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ALMA</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu8aa0ad29c1aef247d70f689e43804a72_335286_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>ALMA</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/alma/</link></image><item><title>Deep [OIII] 88um and dust continuum observations of two remarkably luminous galaxies at z~10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_alma_beasts_hashimoto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_alma_beasts_hashimoto/</guid><description>&lt;p>ALMA | Cycle 8 | 17.8hrs | PI - T. Hashimoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose [OIII] 88 um and dust continuum observations of two remarkably UV-luminous (MUV=-23) galaxies at z~10. Our targets are carefully selected from the brand-new COSMOS2020 catalogue equipped with deep and unprecedentedly-wide optical to near-infrared data, the best suitable to find the rarest, brightest galaxies. Our two candidates have 1) sharp Lyman break features; 2) IRAC detection; 3) tight photo-z solutions. The volume density of these objects is consistent with the bright-end of the UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z=9-10 that suggests a double power-law.
We aim to identify these objects by [OIII], which is proven to be the best FIR line to observe z&amp;gt;8 galaxies. A successful detection will confirm the power-law nature of the UVLF for the first time by spectroscopy. This has significant implication in the field of galaxy formation as they would represent a transition before significant dust attenuation and mass quenching. We will also directly observe the dust continuum,which is crucial to test the dust-poor hypothesis as the physical origins of the brightest galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resolving the rapid quenching of star formation in the local Universe</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2020_alma_psb_rowlands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2020_alma_psb_rowlands/</guid><description>&lt;p>ALMA | Cycle 7 | 10.7hrs | PI - K. Rowlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One key problem in galaxy evolution is how and why galaxies stop forming stars. However, the exact mechanisms that lead to the disruption of the gas supply, the relative importance of different quenching mechanisms, and the timescales involved are still poorly understood. Post-starburst galaxies are an ideal laboratory to study the galaxy transition process as they have undergone a recent, rapid shutdown in star formation, and are expected to be devoid of cold gas. Surprisingly, many of these galaxies still host large reservoirs of molecular gas, which challenges our current picture of quenching. Recent studies of these galaxies suffered from an aperture bias - we know rapid quenching of star formation occured in some regions but we only have unresolved measurements of the molecular gas. We propose to map CO(1-0) emission at 2.5&amp;quot; resolution matched to optical integral field spectroscopic data from the MaNGA survey in 13 post-starburst galaxies. We will determine whether a low gas fraction in post-starburst regions is the cause of quenching, or if gas is forming stars inefficiently. Only the combination of ALMA and optical IFU observations can reveal what processes are responsible for stopping star formation in galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>