<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured | John R. Weaver</title>
    <link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/featured/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Featured</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hud2deb781e67c92bf3648344da244734d_232030_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Featured</title>
      <link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/featured/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSMOS2020</title>
      <link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-galaxy-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-galaxy-catalog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COSMOS survey is one the longest-running galaxy surveys. Over two decades, we have collected observations of x-ray, optical, infrared, and radio light to obtain galaxy distances and understand their evolution over 13.7 billion years of cosmic history. I lead the 2020 edition of the master galaxy catalog, using bleeding-edge galaxy model-fitting techniques from The Farmer to measure galaxy properties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Stellar Mass Assembly History Over 13 Billion Years</title>
      <link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-smf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-smf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Farmer</title>
      <link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/thefarmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/thefarmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;publication-in-preparation&#34;&gt;PUBLICATION IN PREPARATION&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the increasing depth and area of galaxy surveys promise definitive high-redshift studies, ever more crowded sources challenge current photometric methodology. Recent work by Lang and Hogg (2016) has provided another toolkit: The Tractor. By leveraging our understanding of galaxy morphologies, the Tractor is able to force galaxy models derived from high-resolution images onto less resolved ones, with superior deblending and robust photometric redshifts ─ advantageous for high-redshift studies. We present the Farmer, a comprehensive software interfacing with The Tractor to detect sources, efficiently determine the best model type for each source, and perform forced photometry in a scalable architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
