<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Academic | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/academic/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Academic</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu12458071943080563402.png</url><title>Academic</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/academic/</link></image><item><title>The First High-z Galaxies from Euclid Have Been Found!</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/post/euclid_lbgs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/post/euclid_lbgs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="to-be-featured-in-aa-special-issue">To be featured in A&amp;amp;A Special Issue&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="arxiv-pre-print-httpsarxivorgabs240513505httpsarxivorgabs240513505">ArXiv pre-print: &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.13505" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.13505&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This paper presents a search for high redshift galaxies from the Euclid Early Release Observations program &amp;ldquo;Magnifying Lens.&amp;rdquo; The 1.5 deg2 area covered by the twin Abell lensing cluster fields is comparable in size to the few other deep near-infrared surveys such as COSMOS, and so provides an opportunity to significantly increase known samples of rare UV-bright galaxies at z≈6−8 (MUV≲−22). Beyond their still uncertain role in reionisation, these UV-bright galaxies are ideal laboratories from which to study galaxy formation and constrain the bright-end of the UV luminosity function. Of the 501994 sources detected from a combined YE, JE, and HE NISP detection image, 168 do not have any appreciable VIS/IE flux. These objects span a range in spectral colours, separated into two classes: 139 extremely red sources; and 29 Lyman-break galaxy candidates. Best-fit redshifts and spectral templates suggest the former is composed of both z≳5 dusty star-forming galaxies and z≈1−3 quiescent systems. The latter is composed of more homogeneous Lyman break galaxies at z≈6−8. In both cases, contamination by L- and T-type dwarfs cannot be ruled out with Euclid images alone. Additional contamination from instrumental persistence is investigated using a novel time series analysis. This work lays the foundation for future searches within the Euclid Deep Fields, where thousands more z≳6 Lyman break systems and extremely red sources will be identified.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The COSMOS2020 Catalog has been published in ApJS!</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/post/c2020_accepted/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/post/c2020_accepted/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="publisher-version-apj-supplement-serieshttpsiopscienceioporgarticle1038471538-4365ac3078">Publisher Version: &lt;a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/1538-4365/ac3078" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ApJ Supplement Series&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="arxiv-pre-print-arxivorgabs211013923httpsarxivorgabs211013923">ArXiv pre-print: &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.13923" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arxiv.org/abs/2110.13923&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="catalog-and-data-products-available-at-the-calet-server-at-iaphttpscosmos2020caletorg">Catalog and Data Products Available at &lt;a href="https://cosmos2020.calet.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the CALET Server at IAP&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Cosmic Evolution Survey (COSMOS) has become a cornerstone of extragalactic astronomy. Since the last public catalog in 2015, a wealth of new imaging and spectroscopic data has been collected in the COSMOS field. This paper describes the collection, processing, and analysis of this new imaging data to produce a new reference photometric redshift catalog. Source detection and multi-wavelength photometry is performed for 1.7 million sources across the 2deg2 of the COSMOS field, ∼966,000 of which are measured with all available broad-band data using both traditional aperture photometric methods and a new profile-fitting photometric extraction tool, The Farmer, which we have developed. A detailed comparison of the two resulting photometric catalogs is presented. Photometric redshifts are computed for all sources in each catalog utilizing two independent photometric redshift codes. Finally, a comparison is made between the performance of the photometric methodologies and of the redshift codes to demonstrate an exceptional degree of self-consistency in the resulting photometric redshifts. The i&amp;lt;21 sources have sub-percent photometric redshift accuracy and even the faintest sources at 25&amp;lt;i&amp;lt;27 reach a precision of 5%. Finally, these results are discussed in the context of previous, current, and future surveys in the COSMOS field. Compared to COSMOS2015, reaches the same photometric redshift precision at almost one magnitude deeper. Both photometric catalogs and their photometric redshift solutions and physical parameters will be made available through the usual astronomical archive systems (ESO Phase 3, IPAC IRSA, and CDS).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We've been awarded JWST Cycle 1 time!</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/post/jwst/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/post/jwst/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="see-the-program-information-on-the-space-telescope-science-institutes-websitehttpswwwstsciedujwstscience-executionprogram-informationid2659">See the Program Information on the &lt;a href="https://www.stsci.edu/jwst/science-execution/program-information?id=2659" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Space Telescope Science Institute&amp;rsquo;s Website&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract:&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We propose restframe UV and optical spectroscopy to confirm redshifts and measure star-formation rates, stellar masses, and dust extinction for the five most luminous galaxies at 9&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;10 over two square degrees of the COSMOS survey. The unique combination of a wide-field near-infrared imaging coupled with new ultra-deep optical and infrared data makes this the most secure sample of 9&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;10 galaxy candidates currently available. However, these objects are too rare to be found by very deep, but smaller surveys with JWST, and the serendipitous discovery of even one such galaxy outside of COSMOS is unlikely from the entirety of planned GTO and ERS programs. These massive, luminous galaxies, seen only 500 million years after the Big Bang, are ideal tracers of the primordial dark matter structures from which they formed and grew. However, their mere existence at these early times challenges the current paradigm of early galaxy formation and evolution. Thus, it is essential to confirm their high redshift nature and reveal the means by which these remarkable cosmic beasts so rapidly built up their stellar mass.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="" srcset="
/post/jwst/goals_hu16855329748160399019.webp 400w,
/post/jwst/goals_hu13880204704549682503.webp 760w,
/post/jwst/goals_hu8993033359202116441.webp 1200w"
src="https://astroweaver.github.io/post/jwst/goals_hu16855329748160399019.webp"
width="760"
height="497"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable class=" img-dark" />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>