<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COI | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/coi/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/coi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>COI</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 11:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu12458071943080563402.png</url><title>COI</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/coi/</link></image><item><title>Galaxy Protoclusters as Drivers of Cosmic Reionization</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_jwst_protocluster_martin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_jwst_protocluster_martin/</guid><description>&lt;p>JWST / NIRCam+NIRSpec | Cycle 1 | 25.2+9.7hrs | PI - C. Martin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The environmental dependence of galaxy properties today requires an accelerated assembly history in high density environments. Protoclusters, the overdense regions of
the universe that ultimately collapse into massive galaxy clusters, contribute a significant fraction of all cosmic star formation during the era of reionization. The galaxy
overdensity may enhance the escape of ionizing photons, making protoclusters crucial in driving the timing and topology of cosmic reionization. We propose to measure
the brightest rest-frame-optical emission lines from spectrosopically-confirmed galaxies comprising the largest overdensity yet identified near the midpoint of cosmic
reionization, z7OD. Eight protocluster members, identified by their Lyman-alpha emission, are the primary targets for these NIRSpec MOS observations, which will
measure rest-frame optical emission lines between the [OII] doublet and hydrogen Balmer alpha lines. We aim to measure the transmission of the IGM in and around an
ionized, cosmic bubble, determine the physical properties of the galaxies that ionized the bubble, and compare them to field galaxies at z &amp;gt; 3.37 (observed
simultaneously). We will measure the Lyman-alpha escape fraction and the Lyman-alpha velocity offset, information required to map spatial variation in IGM transmission.
Protoclusters at this redshift are predicted to contain significant amount of cold gas, possibly triggering high specific star formation rates and accelerating the chemical
evolution of the galaxies; ideas we will test by directly measuring diagnostic emission-line ratios&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Webb Epoch of Reionization Lyman-alpha Survey (WERLS)</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_werls_casey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_werls_casey/</guid><description>&lt;p>NASA Key Strategic Mission Support | Keck/MOSFIRE+LRIS | 29N | PI - C. Casey &amp;amp; J. Kartaltepe&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose the Webb Epoch of Reionization Lyman-alpha Survey (WERLS), a spectroscopic redshift survey using MOSFIRE and LRIS, targeting ~800 galaxies embedded within the Epoch of Reionization (EoR) at 6&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;8. Our goals are to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>conduct a census of Ly-alpha emission in already identified luminous EoR galaxies (M_UV&amp;lt; -21) to map ionization bubbles in the intergalactic medium at a time when the Universe was partially ionized and on scales much larger than the expected size of ionization bubbles,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>directly compare the Ly-alpha-inferred location of ionization bubbles to underlying galaxy density maps that will be measured via deep Webb NIRCam imaging to directly constrain the galaxies responsible for reionization, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>increase the number of spectroscopically-confirmed bright EoR sources by a factor of ~2-4x within 6&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;8 via firm detection of Ly-alpha emission, which will critically inform photometric redshift calibration of fainter EoR-era galaxies exclusively detected by Webb.
This survey will be conducted in preparation for, and in conjunction with, the largest and deepest extragalactic imaging surveys from the James Webb Space Telescope Cycle 1 and ERS programs covering 0.7deg^2: COSMOS-Webb, PRIMER-UDS, and CEERS. These programs aim to reveal several thousands of EoR galaxies and map their distribution in large scale structure on 10-100Mpc scales. WERLS will focus on already-identified bright galaxies in these surveys, which likely trace the highest mass overdensities to be found by Webb; detection of Lyman-alpha will reveal whether or not they live in ionized bubbles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Remarkably UV-bright Galaxies at z=9-10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_beasts_casey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_beasts_casey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keck/MOSFIRE | 2N | PI - C. Casey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose Keck MOSFIRE J-band spectroscopy for four UV-bright (H=24.5&amp;ndash;25.4 mag) novel photometric candidates at z=9-10 from the new COSMOS2020 catalogs, with deeper, homogeneous near-IR and ultra-deep optical coverage that allowed for the identification of such rare, extraordinary candidates. All candidates have (a) clear Lyman-break features from Y to H bands, (b) IRAC detection, (c) tight distributions in PDF(z) at z=9-10, (d) inconsistency with common high-z galaxy contaminants (low-mass stars and dusty lower-z galaxies), and (e) are estimated to sit at z&amp;gt;9 with four independent fits to their photometry. The volume density of these four candidates is also consistent with the bright-end of the latest UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z=9-10. With the proposed observations, we will achieve the following three major goals: 1) redshift confirmation and thus the power-law nature of the UVLF at z=9-10; 2) testing if UV-bright galaxies at z=9-10 reside in ionized bubbles; and 3) if they host AGN measured via the Nv1243 line. Importantly, our targets are &amp;gt; 10-20 times brighter than the only other source confirmed with line emission at these redshifts. The spectroscopic confirmation of our targets will provide essential constraints on the bright/massive-end of luminosity/mass function at z&amp;gt;9 and the cold dark matter formation of early, massive galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Remarkably UV-bright Galaxies at z=9-10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_beasts_fujimoto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_beasts_fujimoto/</guid><description>&lt;p>Subaru/SWIMS | 1.5N | PI - S. Fujimoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Awarded back-up instrument time on SWIMS)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose Keck MOSFIRE J-band spectroscopy for five UV-bright (H =24.5–25.4 mag) novel photometric candidates at z = 9 − 10 from the brand new COSMOS2020 catalogs, now benefitting from homogeneous near-IR and ultra-deep optical coverage that allowed for such identification. All candidates have clear Lyman-break features from Y to H bands, IRAC detection, tight distributions in PDF(z) at z = 9 − 10, the inconsistency with the templates of the stellar and dusty galaxy at lower redshift, and are confirmed at z &amp;gt; 9 with four independent redshift estimates. The volume density of these five candidates is also consistent with the bright-end of the latest UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z = 9 − 10. With the proposed observations, we will achieve the following two major goals: 1) confirming the redshift and the power-law nature of the UVLF at z = 9 − 10, and 2) testing if UV-bright galaxies at z = 9 − 10 host AGN via the Nv1243 line. Importantly, our targets are &amp;gt; ×10–20 brighter than the only other source confirmed at z = 9.11. Our targets will provide essential constraints on the bright/massive-end of luminosity/mass function at z &amp;gt; 9 and the CDM scenario for the formation of early galaxies, once at least one of their redshifts are confirmed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep [OIII] 88um and dust continuum observations of two remarkably luminous galaxies at z~10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_alma_beasts_hashimoto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_alma_beasts_hashimoto/</guid><description>&lt;p>ALMA | Cycle 8 | 17.8hrs | PI - T. Hashimoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose [OIII] 88 um and dust continuum observations of two remarkably UV-luminous (MUV=-23) galaxies at z~10. Our targets are carefully selected from the brand-new COSMOS2020 catalogue equipped with deep and unprecedentedly-wide optical to near-infrared data, the best suitable to find the rarest, brightest galaxies. Our two candidates have 1) sharp Lyman break features; 2) IRAC detection; 3) tight photo-z solutions. The volume density of these objects is consistent with the bright-end of the UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z=9-10 that suggests a double power-law.
We aim to identify these objects by [OIII], which is proven to be the best FIR line to observe z&amp;gt;8 galaxies. A successful detection will confirm the power-law nature of the UVLF for the first time by spectroscopy. This has significant implication in the field of galaxy formation as they would represent a transition before significant dust attenuation and mass quenching. We will also directly observe the dust continuum,which is crucial to test the dust-poor hypothesis as the physical origins of the brightest galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep spectroscopy of bright red massive quiescent galaxies at z~2.5-3 in COSMOS</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_vlt_z3qg_valentino/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_vlt_z3qg_valentino/</guid><description>&lt;p>VLT/XSHOOTER | 56.0hrs| PI - F. Valentino&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose to observe with X-Shooter a statistical sample of 7 bright (K&amp;lt;21 mag), massive (M*&amp;gt;1e11 Msun), and quiescent (sSFR&amp;lt;1e-9.5/yr) galaxies at z~2.5-3 selected from the brand-new COSMOS2020 catalog. The sample encloses all the galaxies in the 2sq.deg. field fulfilling these criteria and spans a range of SED shapes consistent with different formation and quenching epochs. From the spectra, we will measure accurate redshifts, ages, stellar velocity dispersions (σ_vel), and estimate possible residual unobscured SFR and/or AGN contamination from emission lines, if present. This will allow us to reconstruct the SFH from the combined spectra+SED modeling and to directly compare them with custom mock observations extracted from simulations for a systematic analysis of the history of formation of these systems. Estimates of σ_vel will also allow for a first test for the existence dynamical scaling relations at such high redshifts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep Subaru HSC z-band imaging of the Euclid/JWST/Roman Deep Field</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_nep_suzuki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_nep_suzuki/</guid><description>&lt;p>Subaru/HSC | 2N | PI - N. Suzuki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We request 2 nights of Subaru Hyper-SuprimeCam to complete z-band observations of the largest multi-wavelength (ugriz) field, Hawaii Two-0 (H20), a contiguous survey covering 20 sq. deg area of two primary Euclid Deep Calibration Fields (NEP and CDFS). A total of 30 nights on the Subaru/HSC and 10 nights on the Keck/DEIMOS telescopes were allocated for this program through the Hawaii TAC which has now completed g-, r-, i- band coverage. This proposal is to complete the z-band photometric survey in the NEP field to the desired depth of 26.5 AB. The z-band data are essential for accurate physical parameter measurements of galaxies at 0 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 3 (e.g., photometric redshift and stellar mass) and selection of galaxies at 3 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 6 . These measurements will allow us to study the evolution of massive galaxies to z~6, estimate the properties of their dark matter haloes through clustering measurements, and find rare objects that are re-ionizing the universe. This is a legacy Euclid program.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploring UV-bright galaxies at z~9-10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_beasts_mobasher/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_beasts_mobasher/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keck/MOSFIRE | 2N | PI - B. Mobasher&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The environmental dependence of galaxy properties today requires an accelerated assembly history in high density environments. Protoclusters, the overdense regions of
the universe that ultimately collapse into massive galaxy clusters, contribute a significant fraction of all cosmic star formation during the era of reionization. The galaxy
overdensity may enhance the escape of ionizing photons, making protoclusters crucial in driving the timing and topology of cosmic reionization. We propose to measure
the brightest rest-frame-optical emission lines from spectrosopically-confirmed galaxies comprising the largest overdensity yet identified near the midpoint of cosmic
reionization, z7OD. Eight protocluster members, identified by their Lyman-alpha emission, are the primary targets for these NIRSpec MOS observations, which will
measure rest-frame optical emission lines between the [OII] doublet and hydrogen Balmer alpha lines. We aim to measure the transmission of the IGM in and around an
ionized, cosmic bubble, determine the physical properties of the galaxies that ionized the bubble, and compare them to field galaxies at z &amp;gt; 3.37 (observed
simultaneously). We will measure the Lyman-alpha escape fraction and the Lyman-alpha velocity offset, information required to map spatial variation in IGM transmission.
Protoclusters at this redshift are predicted to contain significant amount of cold gas, possibly triggering high specific star formation rates and accelerating the chemical
evolution of the galaxies; ideas we will test by directly measuring diagnostic emission-line ratios&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First accurate constraint of cold dust and gas properties in the EoR</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_dust_liu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_dust_liu/</guid><description>&lt;p>NOEMA | 20.0hrs | PI - D. Liu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How galaxies grow their metals and stellar masses in the first few hundred million years is a fundamental question. The evolution of cold gas depletion time, gas fraction and dust temperature is well established out to redshift z&lt;del>5, however, little is known in the epoch of reionization (EoR). The insufficient number of spectroscopically identified EoR galaxies and their extreme faintness in dust continuum are the main reasons hampering an accurate determination of their dust and cold gas properties. Here we select the newly-confirmed, 1.3mm-brightest and most-massive/dusty EoR target (with robust [CII] spec-z=7.31) among the 40+ known spec-z&amp;gt;6.5 galaxies in the EoR to detect its Rayleigh-Jeans (RJ) tail rest-frame 250um flux at 2mm using 20 hours of NOEMA time. This is the first RJ dust study in the EoR, and will make the target the first golden reference for: a) accurate (cold) dust and gas properties; b) CII vs. RJ dust continuum cold gas mass calibration for high-z CII studies; c) cold gas depletion time, gas fraction and dust temperature evolution towards z&lt;/del>7.3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Follow-up spectroscopy for a protocluster of quiescent galaxies at z = 2.8</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_ito/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_ito/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keck/MOSFIRE | 1N | PI - K. Ito&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose to conduct MOSFIRE spectroscopy for an overdense
region of massive (log M⋆/M⊙&amp;gt;10.5) quiescent galaxies at z= 2.8, which is newly found from the latest COSMOS2020 catalog. Though
many passive galaxies exist in local
galaxy clusters, most known protoclusters are found by only star
-forming galaxies. Protoclusters consisting of quiescent
galaxies had not been found at
z &amp;gt; 2. The high-redshift structures of quiescent galaxies are unique a
nd expected to
provide an insight into the (proto)cluster evolution and the connec
tion between the environment and the quenching. Our
goals of this proposal are 1). to spectroscopically confirm the str
ucture from Balmer absorption lines of 12 quiescent
galaxies therein and 2). to explore their star formation history thr
ough the observed spectrum and plenty of multi-band
photometry data. The derived star formation history will conclude
the primordial environmental effect on the stellar age
and constrain the progenitor of this structure. If this structur
e is spectroscopically confirmed, this is the most distant
protocluster of quiescent galaxies, which will be an ideal laboratory
for conducting the follow-up observation, such as by
ALMA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The emergence of the first quiescent galaxies - take 2</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_tanaka/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_tanaka/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keck/MOSFIRE | 2N | PI - M. Tanaka&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose for 2 nights of Keck/MOSFIRE observations to follow-up a z ∼ 4.7 quiescent galaxy in COSMOS as part of our on-going campaign to build a sample of distant quenched/quenching galaxies. From our previous runs (S17B- 106, S18B-040, S20B-031),(1) we have confirmed three z = 4.010, 3.99 and 3.775 galaxies, all of which are the highest redshift quiescent galaxies known to date, and (2) we have measured stellar velocity dispersions of the z = 4.010 and 3.99 galaxies, revealing that the mass in the core of these galaxies does not significantly evolve over the last 12 Gyr, which is consistent with the 2-phase formation scenario. Building upon three papers from our previous runs (Tanaka+ 2019, Valentino+ 2020, Tanaka+ in prep), we now propose to observe the most distant quenching galaxy candidate from our sample in COSMOS at z ∼ 4.7 based on the latest COSMOS2020 catalog with superb photometric quality. We aim (1) to spectroscopically confirm the emergence of the first quiescent galaxies when the Universe was only 1.2 Gyr old, and (2) to fully capture the Balmer break in the K-band to measure their star formation epoch and timescale, which will, combined with state-of-the-art simulations, give us new insights into key physics of very early quenching.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncovering a unique population of gas giants at &lt;z>=1.2</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_giants_kokorev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_giants_kokorev/</guid><description>&lt;p>NOEMA | 8.0hrs | PI - V. Kokorev&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have discovered a new population of galaxies in the distant Universe (z&amp;gt;1) with extremely cold dust temperatures, similar to the coldest galaxies in the local Universe. Taken at face value, this corresponds to very large dust masses and, as a result, extreme gas fractions. The nature of these galaxies is puzzling, as such extreme gas enrichment are not predicted by either theoretical models or existing empirical observations. We propose to infer and confirm the gas mass (Mgas), and the dust mass (Mdust) for two &amp;ldquo;gas-giants&amp;rdquo; at &lt;z>=1.2, that lie on the main-sequence of star-formation. Our goal is to detect the CO(2-1) emission line, as well as the dust continuum at rest frame 1.2 mm, with a set of efficiently designed observations.These observations will target a robustly selected, representative sample of these objects, to act as a pilot study into these unique and unexpected systems. In particular with the proposed observations we will 1) explore and put constraints the dust/gas masses and fractions in these giants 2) confirm the extreme nature of these objects to facilitate a larger follow-up proposal to observe the full population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A pilot study of AGN disk reverberation mapping at redshift z=1</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_lco_vqso_santisteban/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_lco_vqso_santisteban/</guid><description>&lt;p>LCO-2m/MuSCAT3 | 1.85N | PI - J. Hernandez Santisteban&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose a pilot study to use the Intensive accretion Disk Reverberation Mapping (IDRM) technique to probe the radial structure of a moderately high redshift quasar, SDSS J0304 ($z=0.99$), using LCO alone. IDRM has successfully combined LCO and Swift monitoring to measure interband continuum lags to study the geometry and infer the properties of $&amp;gt;$10 low-redshift ($z&amp;lt;0.1$) AGN disks. Because this target is more than an order of magnitude more luminous, the lags should be commensurately larger, and thus should be measurable even without Swift to anchor the UV. However that has not been definitively demonstrated. If successful, this program will allow us to extend local sample measurements of the inferred disk size and temperature structure to higher mass ($\sim10^9$ M$_\odot$) and redshift. It will also provide a key proof of concept for the LSST program, which should provide comparable data on thousands of AGN.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A pilot study of AGN disk reverberation mapping at redshift z=1</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_liverpool_vqso_santisteban/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_liverpool_vqso_santisteban/</guid><description>&lt;p>Liverpool Telescope | 26.0hrs | PI - J. Hernandez Santisteban&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose a pilot study to use Intensive accretion Disc Reverberation Mapping (IDRM) to probe the radial structure of a moderately-high redshift quasar, SDSS J2353 (z = 0.99). IDRM has successfully combined ground-based and Swift monitoring to measure interband continuum lags to study the geometry and infer the properties of &amp;gt;10 low-redshift (z &amp;lt; 0.15) AGN discs. Because SDSS J2353 is more than an order of magnitude more luminous, the lags should be commensurately larger, and thus should be measurable even without Swift to anchor the UV. However that has not yet been definitively demonstrated. If successful, this program will allow us to extend the local sample measurements of disc size and temperature structure to higher mass (∼ 109 M⊙), luminosity (∼ 1047 erg s−1) and redshift. It will also provide a key proof of concept for LSST, which should provide comparable data for many thousands of AGN.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Remarkably UV-bright Galaxies at z=9-10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_vlt_beasts_fujimoto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_vlt_beasts_fujimoto/</guid><description>&lt;p>VLT/XSHOOTER | 25.7hrs | PI - S. Fuijimoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose X-shooter observations for four UV-bright (H=24.5-25.4 mag) novel candidates at z=9-10 from the brand new COSMOS2020 catalogue, now benefitting from homogeneous near-IR and ultra-deep optical coverage. All candidates have clear Lyman-break features, IRAC detection, tight distributions in PDF(z) at z=9-10, the inconsistency with any stellar templates and lower-z galaxy, and are confirmed at z&amp;gt;9 with four independent redshift estimates. The volume density of these four candidates is also consistent with the bright-end of the latest UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z=9-10. We will 1) confirm the redshift and the power-law nature of the UVLF at z=9-10; and test if UV-bright galaxies at z=9-10 2) reside in ionized bubbles; and 3) host AGN via the Nv1243 line. Our targets will provide essential constraints on the bright/massive-end of luminosity/mass function at z&amp;gt;9 and the CDM scenario for the formation of early galaxies, once at least one is confirmed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chasing big bubbles: the confirmation of a bright z=9.8 galaxy</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_noema_beasts_valentino/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_noema_beasts_valentino/</guid><description>&lt;p>NOEMA | 30.0hrs | PI - F. Valentino&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We request 30h of NOEMA/2mm time to spectroscopically confirm the redshift of a novel and robust UV- bright (MUV=-22.9 mag) galaxy candidate at z=9.82 from the new COSMOS2020 catalog. The candidate is massive (log(M/Msun)=10.5), highly star-forming (log(SFR/Msun/yr)=2.2), and shows a tight redshift PDF, which can be covered at 90% with a single NOEMA frequency setting targeting [CII]. These properties suggest a sufficient metal enrichment and encourage the search for this line and its underlying dust continuum emission. If confirmed, this will be a redshift record-breaking discovery, while the [CII] and dust IR luminosity will give us insight into the gas and obscured SFR. This will allow us to explore the SFR or MUV-L[CII] and IRX-beta relations at the unprecedented z~10 regime. This would also support the role of ultra-bright sources to generate large reionization bubbles. The target is 1.5dex more star forming than the only other source confirmed with FIR lines at z=9.11 and it does not suffer from lensing uncertainties. The large bandwidth and arcsec resolution of NOEMA are optimal to carry out this project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resolving the rapid quenching of star formation in the local Universe</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2020_alma_psb_rowlands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2020_alma_psb_rowlands/</guid><description>&lt;p>ALMA | Cycle 7 | 10.7hrs | PI - K. Rowlands&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One key problem in galaxy evolution is how and why galaxies stop forming stars. However, the exact mechanisms that lead to the disruption of the gas supply, the relative importance of different quenching mechanisms, and the timescales involved are still poorly understood. Post-starburst galaxies are an ideal laboratory to study the galaxy transition process as they have undergone a recent, rapid shutdown in star formation, and are expected to be devoid of cold gas. Surprisingly, many of these galaxies still host large reservoirs of molecular gas, which challenges our current picture of quenching. Recent studies of these galaxies suffered from an aperture bias - we know rapid quenching of star formation occured in some regions but we only have unresolved measurements of the molecular gas. We propose to map CO(1-0) emission at 2.5&amp;quot; resolution matched to optical integral field spectroscopic data from the MaNGA survey in 13 post-starburst galaxies. We will determine whether a low gas fraction in post-starburst regions is the cause of quenching, or if gas is forming stars inefficiently. Only the combination of ALMA and optical IFU observations can reveal what processes are responsible for stopping star formation in galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>