<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NOEMA | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/noema/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/noema/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>NOEMA</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu8aa0ad29c1aef247d70f689e43804a72_335286_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>NOEMA</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/noema/</link></image><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Remarkably UV-bright Galaxies at z=9-10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_beasts_casey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_keck_beasts_casey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keck/MOSFIRE | 2N | PI - C. Casey&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose Keck MOSFIRE J-band spectroscopy for four UV-bright (H=24.5&amp;ndash;25.4 mag) novel photometric candidates at z=9-10 from the new COSMOS2020 catalogs, with deeper, homogeneous near-IR and ultra-deep optical coverage that allowed for the identification of such rare, extraordinary candidates. All candidates have (a) clear Lyman-break features from Y to H bands, (b) IRAC detection, (c) tight distributions in PDF(z) at z=9-10, (d) inconsistency with common high-z galaxy contaminants (low-mass stars and dusty lower-z galaxies), and (e) are estimated to sit at z&amp;gt;9 with four independent fits to their photometry. The volume density of these four candidates is also consistent with the bright-end of the latest UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z=9-10. With the proposed observations, we will achieve the following three major goals: 1) redshift confirmation and thus the power-law nature of the UVLF at z=9-10; 2) testing if UV-bright galaxies at z=9-10 reside in ionized bubbles; and 3) if they host AGN measured via the Nv1243 line. Importantly, our targets are &amp;gt; 10-20 times brighter than the only other source confirmed with line emission at these redshifts. The spectroscopic confirmation of our targets will provide essential constraints on the bright/massive-end of luminosity/mass function at z&amp;gt;9 and the cold dark matter formation of early, massive galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First accurate constraint of cold dust and gas properties in the EoR</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_dust_liu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_dust_liu/</guid><description>&lt;p>NOEMA | 20.0hrs | PI - D. Liu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How galaxies grow their metals and stellar masses in the first few hundred million years is a fundamental question. The evolution of cold gas depletion time, gas fraction and dust temperature is well established out to redshift z~5, however, little is known in the epoch of reionization (EoR). The insufficient number of spectroscopically identified EoR galaxies and their extreme faintness in dust continuum are the main reasons hampering an accurate determination of their dust and cold gas properties. Here we select the newly-confirmed, 1.3mm-brightest and most-massive/dusty EoR target (with robust [CII] spec-z=7.31) among the 40+ known spec-z&amp;gt;6.5 galaxies in the EoR to detect its Rayleigh-Jeans (RJ) tail rest-frame 250um flux at 2mm using 20 hours of NOEMA time. This is the first RJ dust study in the EoR, and will make the target the first golden reference for: a) accurate (cold) dust and gas properties; b) CII vs. RJ dust continuum cold gas mass calibration for high-z CII studies; c) cold gas depletion time, gas fraction and dust temperature evolution towards z~7.3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncovering a unique population of gas giants at &lt;z>=1.2</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_giants_kokorev/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_noema_giants_kokorev/</guid><description>&lt;p>NOEMA | 8.0hrs | PI - V. Kokorev&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have discovered a new population of galaxies in the distant Universe (z&amp;gt;1) with extremely cold dust temperatures, similar to the coldest galaxies in the local Universe. Taken at face value, this corresponds to very large dust masses and, as a result, extreme gas fractions. The nature of these galaxies is puzzling, as such extreme gas enrichment are not predicted by either theoretical models or existing empirical observations. We propose to infer and confirm the gas mass (Mgas), and the dust mass (Mdust) for two &amp;ldquo;gas-giants&amp;rdquo; at &lt;z>=1.2, that lie on the main-sequence of star-formation. Our goal is to detect the CO(2-1) emission line, as well as the dust continuum at rest frame 1.2 mm, with a set of efficiently designed observations.These observations will target a robustly selected, representative sample of these objects, to act as a pilot study into these unique and unexpected systems. In particular with the proposed observations we will 1) explore and put constraints the dust/gas masses and fractions in these giants 2) confirm the extreme nature of these objects to facilitate a larger follow-up proposal to observe the full population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chasing big bubbles: the confirmation of a bright z=9.8 galaxy</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_noema_beasts_valentino/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_noema_beasts_valentino/</guid><description>&lt;p>NOEMA | 30.0hrs | PI - F. Valentino&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We request 30h of NOEMA/2mm time to spectroscopically confirm the redshift of a novel and robust UV- bright (MUV=-22.9 mag) galaxy candidate at z=9.82 from the new COSMOS2020 catalog. The candidate is massive (log(M/Msun)=10.5), highly star-forming (log(SFR/Msun/yr)=2.2), and shows a tight redshift PDF, which can be covered at 90% with a single NOEMA frequency setting targeting [CII]. These properties suggest a sufficient metal enrichment and encourage the search for this line and its underlying dust continuum emission. If confirmed, this will be a redshift record-breaking discovery, while the [CII] and dust IR luminosity will give us insight into the gas and obscured SFR. This will allow us to explore the SFR or MUV-L[CII] and IRX-beta relations at the unprecedented z~10 regime. This would also support the role of ultra-bright sources to generate large reionization bubbles. The target is 1.5dex more star forming than the only other source confirmed with FIR lines at z=9.11 and it does not suffer from lensing uncertainties. The large bandwidth and arcsec resolution of NOEMA are optimal to carry out this project.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>