<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VLT | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/vlt/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/vlt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>VLT</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu8aa0ad29c1aef247d70f689e43804a72_335286_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>VLT</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/vlt/</link></image><item><title>Deep spectroscopy of bright red massive quiescent galaxies at z~2.5-3 in COSMOS</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_vlt_z3qg_valentino/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_vlt_z3qg_valentino/</guid><description>&lt;p>VLT/XSHOOTER | 56.0hrs| PI - F. Valentino&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose to observe with X-Shooter a statistical sample of 7 bright (K&amp;lt;21 mag), massive (M*&amp;gt;1e11 Msun), and quiescent (sSFR&amp;lt;1e-9.5/yr) galaxies at z~2.5-3 selected from the brand-new COSMOS2020 catalog. The sample encloses all the galaxies in the 2sq.deg. field fulfilling these criteria and spans a range of SED shapes consistent with different formation and quenching epochs. From the spectra, we will measure accurate redshifts, ages, stellar velocity dispersions (σ_vel), and estimate possible residual unobscured SFR and/or AGN contamination from emission lines, if present. This will allow us to reconstruct the SFH from the combined spectra+SED modeling and to directly compare them with custom mock observations extracted from simulations for a systematic analysis of the history of formation of these systems. Estimates of σ_vel will also allow for a first test for the existence dynamical scaling relations at such high redshifts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Remarkably UV-bright Galaxies at z=9-10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_vlt_beasts_fujimoto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2021_vlt_beasts_fujimoto/</guid><description>&lt;p>VLT/XSHOOTER | 25.7hrs | PI - S. Fuijimoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose X-shooter observations for four UV-bright (H=24.5-25.4 mag) novel candidates at z=9-10 from the brand new COSMOS2020 catalogue, now benefitting from homogeneous near-IR and ultra-deep optical coverage. All candidates have clear Lyman-break features, IRAC detection, tight distributions in PDF(z) at z=9-10, the inconsistency with any stellar templates and lower-z galaxy, and are confirmed at z&amp;gt;9 with four independent redshift estimates. The volume density of these four candidates is also consistent with the bright-end of the latest UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z=9-10. We will 1) confirm the redshift and the power-law nature of the UVLF at z=9-10; and test if UV-bright galaxies at z=9-10 2) reside in ionized bubbles; and 3) host AGN via the Nv1243 line. Our targets will provide essential constraints on the bright/massive-end of luminosity/mass function at z&amp;gt;9 and the CDM scenario for the formation of early galaxies, once at least one is confirmed.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>