<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>invited | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/invited/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/invited/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>invited</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu8e71e1b536ffcaa57bdea0990ac1b238_79891_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>invited</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/invited/</link></image><item><title>Turtles all the way down: perspectives on precision photometry to explore the early red universe with JWST</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/firstlight2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/firstlight2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coming Soon&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: Insights into galaxy formation and growth in the first 10 billion years</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/leiden2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/leiden2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coming Soon&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Discovering the origins of the first massive galaxies with JWST</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/eso2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/eso2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recent observations of the early universe have suggested the impossible: an abundance of ultra-massive, dead galaxies already within 1.5 billion years after the big bang. These ‘cosmic beasts’ must have been among the first galaxies to form, assembling their mass in a luminous burst of star-formation – releasing enough energy to reionize ‘bubbles’ of intergalactic hydrogen &amp;lt; 500 Myr after the Big Bang. Yet, their existence challenges contemporary models of galaxy formation. I will utilize the first observations with JWST to identify their star-forming progenitors, characterize their properties, assess their contribution to reionization, and critically test models of galaxy formation. My Cycle 1 program to observe five massive z ∼ 9 beasts is uniquely suited to the task, and will provide insight into the formation of the first massive galaxies to light up the cosmos.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: A next-generation catalog to explore the 1&lt;z&lt;8 universe</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/caltech2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/caltech2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The COSMOS field has proved to be one of the cornerstone surveys in extragalactic astronomy.
Since our last public catalog in 2015, a wealth of new imaging and spectroscopic data has been
collected in COSMOS. We describe the collection, processing, and analysis of the best available
imaging data in COSMOS over 39 bands and produce a new reference photometric redshift
catalog. Powerful new constraints are made possible from the ultra-deep optical imaging with
Hyper Suprime-Cam, UltraVISTA near-infrared Ks imaging at least 1 magnitude deeper than in
2015, and the inclusion of all Spitzer IRAC infrared imaging ever taken on COSMOS. We find
significant improvement in our astrometric reference from 2015 by utilizing Gaia DR1. From this
reprocessed data, we perform source detection and photometry for 1 million sources across 2 deg2
of the COSMOS field, using both traditional aperture photometric methods and a new profile-fitting
photometric measurement tool we have developed. In addition to a detailed comparison of both
methods, we report the achievement of sub-percent accuracy in our derived photometric redshifts
at i &amp;lt; 22.5 AB and at 25 &amp;lt; i &amp;lt; 27 of less than 5 per-cent. Encouraged by this result, we present
measurements of the deepest wide-field NIR-selected galaxy number counts as well as galaxy
stellar masses with unprecedented statistical confidence out to z~6. Finally, we demonstrate the
power of this ultra-deep multi-wavelength survey with a first look at the cosmological evolution of
galaxy growth via the galaxy stellar mass function with greater constraints than ever before
possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: A panchromatic view of the Universe to z~10 from two complementary catalogs</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/iap2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/iap2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The COSMOS field has proven to be one of the cornerstone surveys in extragalactic astronomy. Since our last public catalog in 2015, a wealth of new imaging and spectroscopic data has been collected in COSMOS. We describe the collection, processing, and analysis of the best available imaging data in COSMOS over 39 bands and produce a new reference photometric redshift catalog. Powerful new constraints are made possible from the ultra-deep optical imaging with Hyper Suprime-Cam, UltraVISTA near-infrared Ks imaging at least 1 magnitude deeper than in 2015, and the inclusion of all Spitzer IRAC infrared imaging ever taken on COSMOS. We find significant improvement in our astrometric reference from 2015 by utilizing Gaia DR1. From this reprocessed data, we perform source detection and photometry for 1 million sources across 2 deg2 of the COSMOS field, using both traditional aperture photometric methods and a new profile-fitting photometric measurement tool we have developed. In addition to a detailed comparison of both methods, we report the achievement of sub-percent accuracy in our derived photometric redshifts at i &amp;lt; 22.5 AB and at 25 &amp;lt; i &amp;lt; 27 of less than 5 per-cent. Encouraged by this result, we present measurements of the deepest wide-field NIR-selected galaxy number counts and discuss three immediate science projects enabled by this work including the galaxy stellar mass and UV luminosity functions as well as constraints on the halo occupation distribution. Important contributions from IAP personnel and facilities in making this work possible will also be highlighted.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>