<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Galaxy Evolution | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/galaxy-evolution/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/galaxy-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Galaxy Evolution</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu8aa0ad29c1aef247d70f689e43804a72_335286_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Galaxy Evolution</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/galaxy-evolution/</link></image><item><title>COSMOS2020</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-galaxy-catalog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-galaxy-catalog/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="paper-httpsarxivorgabs211013923">PAPER: &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.13923" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.13923&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="catalogs-httpscosmos2020caletorg">CATALOGS: &lt;a href="https://cosmos2020.calet.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://cosmos2020.calet.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The COSMOS survey is one the longest-running galaxy surveys. Over two decades, we have collected observations of x-ray, optical, infrared, and radio light to obtain galaxy distances and understand their evolution over 13.7 billion years of cosmic history. I lead the 2020 edition of the master galaxy catalog, using bleeding-edge galaxy model-fitting techniques from The Farmer to measure galaxy properties.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploring the Origins of Galaxy Bimodality at z&lt;0.1</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/psb_manga/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/psb_manga/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="link-to-thesisweaver_mphysthesispdf">&lt;a href="Weaver_MPhysThesis.pdf">LINK TO THESIS&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Post-starburst Galaxies (PSBs) are characterised by a lack of massive, young blue stars and a large fraction of intermediate mass A- and F-type stars. They are interpreted as a population of galaxies which have recently undergone a major episode of star formation, and their study may elucidate the nature of galaxy bimodality.
We employ a principal component analysis to study a sample of 32 low redshift (0.01 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 0.11) PSBs selected with SDSS DR 7 single-fibre spectroscopy and observed with MaNGA integral field spectroscopy. Morphologies are examined to characterise the sample, finding a mixture of starforming and quiescent parameters, indicative of tran- sition. We find that this rich sample exhibits strong radial gradients in stellar age, as measured by the principal components (PC) corresponding to the 4000-Å break strength and excess Hδ absorption. To examine the extent of aperture bias, we com- pare these two properties between the DR 7 and MaNGA spectra, integrated over 3&amp;quot; and the full aperture, finding evidence for systematics and radial gradients. We em- ploy two stellar population synthesis codes (BC03, FSPS) to test the manner in which star-formation proceeded, either as a single radially evolving burst, or coeval with varying burst strengths.
Achieved here for the first time, we find a remarkable consistency between the models and gradients, suggesting complex and diverse star-formation histories. We show that this method, coupled with an increased sample size, is well-suited to elucidate the real nature of these strange and peculiar objects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Galaxy Stellar Mass Assembly History Over 13 Billion Years</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-smf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/cosmos2020-smf/</guid><description/></item><item><title>History and Destiny of a Major Merger Remnant</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/ngc7252/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/ngc7252/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="paper-httpsarxivorgabs180109691">PAPER: &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1801.09691" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://arxiv.org/abs/1801.09691&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>NGC7252, which is one of the nearest major-merger galaxy remnants, is an ideal laboratory to study the processes inherent to the transformation of disc galaxies to ellipticals as observed about ~1Gyr after the collision. We obtained wide-field IFU spectroscopy with the VLT-VIMOS integral-field spectrograph covering the central 50&amp;quot;x50&amp;quot; of NGC7252 to map the stellar and ionised gas kinematics, and the distribution and conditions of the ionised gas, revealing the extent of ongoing star formation and recent star formation history. We find that the inner gas disc is not counter-rotating with respect to the stars and that the stellar kinematics appear complex with a clear indication of a prolate-like rotation component suggesting a polar merger configuration. The ongoing star formation rate is 2.2+-0.6 M_sun/yr and implies a typical depletion time of 2Gyr given the molecular gas content. Furthermore, the spatially-resolved star formation history suggests a slight radial dependence, moving outwards at later times. We confirm a large AGN-ionised gas cloud previously discovered 5kpc south of the nucleus, and find higher ionisation also at the galaxy centre relative to the surrounding gas disc. Although the higher ionisation towards the centre is potentially degenerate within the central star forming ring, it may be associated with a low-luminosity AGN. Although NGC7252 has been classified as post-starburst galaxy at the centre, the elliptical-like major-merger remnant still appears very active. A central kpc-scale gas disc has presumably re-formed quickly within the last 100Myr after final coalescence. The disc features ongoing star formation, implying Gyr long timescale to reach the red sequence through gas consumption alone. While NGC7252 is useful to probe the transformation from discs to ellipticals, it is not well-suited to study the transformation from blue to red at this point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Investigating Star-forming Complexes in a Nearby Dwarf Irregular Galaxy</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/ngc1427a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/ngc1427a/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="link-to-postermmo_cometpng">&lt;a href="mmo_comet.png">LINK TO POSTER&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It is well established that galactic clusters provide dynamic environments in which to examine galaxy evolution. The starbursting dwarf irregular NGC 1427A presents an interesting case as it is being pulled into the nearby Fornax cluster at supersonic speeds, producing a visibly exceptional star formation rate and notably blue colors. It has been suggested that the highly deformed structure of NGC 1427A is due to ram pressure stripping as a result of interacting with a super-heated ICM provided by several nearby elliptical galaxies. The gas density profile of its leading edge is similar to a &amp;ldquo;bow-shock&amp;rdquo;, containing several dozen super-star clusters (SSCs) and thousands of smaller star forming clusters. It is clearly evident that the properties of NGC 1427A change rapidly over relatively short distances. Using dithered HST/ACS images in Sloan equivalent g&amp;rsquo; r&amp;rsquo; i&amp;rsquo; z&amp;rsquo; and Hα filters, we present a morphological and photometric study of NGC 1427A using a novel approach in which stellar properties are measured from sources grouped within localized regions. Apertures are fitted for ~5000 sources at 4σ using a filter-combined master image. Four characteristic regions are chosen to study stellar properties, selected interactively through DS9. We then introduce COMET, a specially-designed source catalog handler for producing graphical figures of each region, cropping both spatially and photometrically. These are then batch-reviewed and analyzed using synthetic isochrones corresponding of each region. Hα bright sources are indicated to illustrate the significance of SSCs. Secondary analysis is carried out using smoothed color maps of source-subtracted diffuse light, yielding penetrative mapping of underlying stellar populations. We show for the first time how the dynamical stellar populations of NGC 1427A differ as a function of position across the surface of the galaxy, ultimately furthering our understanding of cluster interactions and the evolution of irregular galaxies. This work is generously supported by NSF grant #1358980.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Searching for Distant Galaxies with Hubble</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/3dhst/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/project/3dhst/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="link-to-posterleiden_threedhstpdf">&lt;a href="leiden_threedhst.pdf">LINK TO POSTER&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>With ever increasing capability, we are now able to push galaxy evolution studies to extreme high redshift (z&amp;gt;6). At these early times, the first galaxies begin forming stars but some of their light is quickly absorbed by the neutral intergalactic medium. We utilise the unique multiplexing capacity of slitless grism spectroscopy to explore large samples of candidate systems (6&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;13) using Bayesian techniques to quantify line detections. We present preliminary results of 29 spectroscopic candidates selected for the first time as extreme high redshift galaxies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="continued-by-julia-tiller-dawn-international-research-experience-student-nsf">Continued by Julia Tiller, DAWN International Research Experience Student (NSF)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Intensive observations required to spectroscopically secure such a faint source necessitates a careful evaluation of the photometry from which the redshift prior is based. Photometric data were re-evaluated by examining individual image cutouts to discount erroneous measurements. Of the 29 galaxies, 3 are found to be outright spurious and 17 are advanced as high-confidence candidates for follow-up observation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Farmer: Improved model-based photometry for the next generation of galaxy surveys</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/publication/2019-amgp-conf-e-9-w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/publication/2019-amgp-conf-e-9-w/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>