<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu8e71e1b536ffcaa57bdea0990ac1b238_79891_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/</link></image><item><title>COSMOS2020: Insights into galaxy formation and growth in the first 10 billion years</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/leiden2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/leiden2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coming Soon&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: New Insights into Galaxy Assembly and Evolution over the first 10 Billion Years</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/aas2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/aas2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The COSMOS field has proved to be one of the cornerstone surveys in extragalactic astronomy. We have built a new photometric redshift catalog COSMOS2020 from the latest ultra-deep imaging from Subaru, VISTA, and Spitzer. We measure 1M sources across the 2deg2 field using both apertures and profile-fitting photometry, pairing each with two SED fitting codes to derive four sets of precise photometric redshifts. We then measure the form and evolution the Galaxy Stellar Mass Function from 0.2 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 7.5 to reveal a strikingly constant rate of mass assembly stretching back into the Epoch of Reionization. We also find new samples of ultra-luminous galaxies at z&amp;gt;7.5 which form the most robust constraints on the UV Luminosity Function at such early times, confirming an excess of luminous sources. Are we witnessing a stage before feedback has suppressed their growth? Such a scenario challenges galaxy formation theory. We will have our answer soon; five of these luminous z~9 galaxies will be followed up with spatially resolved spectroscopy in the Cycle 1 JWST NIRSpec program BEASTS (PI:Weaver) where we will confirm this excess and reveal the mechanisms responsible for their fantastic growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Discovering the origins of the first massive galaxies with JWST</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/eso2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/eso2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recent observations of the early universe have suggested the impossible: an abundance of ultra-massive, dead galaxies already within 1.5 billion years after the big bang. These ‘cosmic beasts’ must have been among the first galaxies to form, assembling their mass in a luminous burst of star-formation – releasing enough energy to reionize ‘bubbles’ of intergalactic hydrogen &amp;lt; 500 Myr after the Big Bang. Yet, their existence challenges contemporary models of galaxy formation. I will utilize the first observations with JWST to identify their star-forming progenitors, characterize their properties, assess their contribution to reionization, and critically test models of galaxy formation. My Cycle 1 program to observe five massive z ∼ 9 beasts is uniquely suited to the task, and will provide insight into the formation of the first massive galaxies to light up the cosmos.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In Search of Fossils: A method to distinguish Quiescent and Dusty Star-forming Galaxies with t-SNE</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/iapml2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/iapml2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Large galaxy surveys have revealed a surprising number of galaxies that have ceased (or quenched) their star-formation, seen as they were when the Universe was only half its current age. However, identifying large, but clean, samples of these “quiescent” galaxies has proven difficult. Their spectral shapes, as measured by broad-band photometric measurements, are highly degenerate with dusty star-forming galaxies whose light is attenuated by thick clouds of dust and present as an interloper population. We describe a new technique for identifying pure samples of quiescent galaxies based upon t-distributed stochastic neighbor embedding (t-SNE), an unsupervised machine learning algorithm for dimensionality reduction. This t-SNE selection provides an improvement in both purity and completeness over traditional methods (e.g. UVJ, NUVrJ) and over spectral template fitting. We find that t-SNE outperforms spectral fitting in 63% of trials at distances where large training samples already exist. Remarkably, we find evidence for increased performance when applying the method to samples in the even more distant Universe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Measurement of the Massive End of z > 8 UV Luminosity Function</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/nam2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/nam2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The current state-of-the-art observational constraints on the evolution of the
most massive and most UV-luminous galaxies at z &amp;gt; 8, and their growth in
relation to large-scale structure and reionization, are derived from
measurements of the UV Luminosity Function (UV LF). Here we present powerful
new constraints on UV emission from sources contributing to the Epoch of
Reionization (EoR) at its very onset, at only 500 Myr after the Big Bang. We
identify these sources with the new COSMOS2020 galaxy catalog, which utilizes
new ultra-deep optical and near-infrared imaging necessary to securely
identify candidate galaxies from the EoR, each with four consistent
measurements of photometric redshift and UV luminosity. Encouraged by this
unprecedented agreement, we confirm a highly significant departure from the
expected Schechter Function form of the UV LF seen in the local universe,
suggesting that galaxy evolution has yet to set in at these early times. An
already approved JWST Cycle 1 program (PI: Weaver) will target five of the
most robust and most UV-luminous (MUV ~ -22.5) z~9 galaxies in COSMOS with
detailed spatially resolved spectroscopy. This ambitious program will
comprehensively map out not only the UV emission from these galaxies, but also
their dust attenuation, morphology, and stellar assembly histories. These new
insights will provide the context necessary to understand the formation of the
most massive, and UV-luminous galaxies in the EoR.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Measurement of the Massive End of z>8 UV Luminosity Function</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/sazerac2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/sazerac2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The current state-of-the-art observational constraints on the evolution of the most massive and most UV-luminous galaxies at z &amp;gt; 8, and their growth in relation to large-scale structure and reionization, are derived from measurements of the UV Luminosity Function (UV LF). Here we present powerful new constraints on UV emission from sources contributing to the Epoch of Reionization (EoR) at its very onset, at only 500 Myr after the Big Bang. We identify these sources with the new COSMOS2020 galaxy catalog, which utilizes new ultra-deep optical and near-infrared imaging necessary to securely identify candidate galaxies from the EoR, each with four consistent measurements of photometric redshift and UV luminosity. Encouraged by this unprecedented agreement, we confirm a highly significant departure from the expected Schechter Function form of the UV LF seen in the local universe, suggesting that galaxy evolution has yet to set in at these early times. An already approved JWST Cycle 1 program (PI: Weaver) will target five of the most robust and most UV-luminous (MUV ~ -22.5) z~9 galaxies in COSMOS with detailed spatially resolved spectroscopy. This ambitious program will comprehensively map out not only the UV emission from these galaxies, but also their dust attenuation, morphology, and stellar assembly histories. These new insights will provide the context necessary to understand the formation of the most massive, and UV-luminous galaxies in the EoR.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Method to Distinguish Quiescent and Dusty Star-forming Galaxies with t-SNE</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/wems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/wems/</guid><description>&lt;p>The current state-of-the-art observational constraints on the evolution of the
most massive and most UV-luminous galaxies at z &amp;gt; 8, and their growth in
relation to large-scale structure and reionization, are derived from
measurements of the UV Luminosity Function (UV LF). Here we present powerful
new constraints on UV emission from sources contributing to the Epoch of
Reionization (EoR) at its very onset, at only 500 Myr after the Big Bang. We
identify these sources with the new COSMOS2020 galaxy catalog, which utilizes
new ultra-deep optical and near-infrared imaging necessary to securely
identify candidate galaxies from the EoR, each with four consistent
measurements of photometric redshift and UV luminosity. Encouraged by this
unprecedented agreement, we confirm a highly significant departure from the
expected Schechter Function form of the UV LF seen in the local universe,
suggesting that galaxy evolution has yet to set in at these early times. An
already approved JWST Cycle 1 program (PI: Weaver) will target five of the
most robust and most UV-luminous (MUV ~ -22.5) z~9 galaxies in COSMOS with
detailed spatially resolved spectroscopy. This ambitious program will
comprehensively map out not only the UV emission from these galaxies, but also
their dust attenuation, morphology, and stellar assembly histories. These new
insights will provide the context necessary to understand the formation of the
most massive, and UV-luminous galaxies in the EoR.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: A panchromatic view of the Universe to z~10 from two complementary catalogs</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/ifa2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/ifa2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The COSMOS field has proven to be one of the cornerstone surveys in extragalactic astronomy. Since our last public catalog in 2015, a wealth of new imaging and spectroscopic data has been collected in COSMOS. We describe the collection, processing, and analysis of the best available imaging data in COSMOS over 39 bands and produce a new reference photometric redshift catalog. Powerful new constraints are made possible from the ultra-deep optical imaging with Hyper Suprime-Cam, UltraVISTA near-infrared Ks imaging at least 1 magnitude deeper than in 2015, and the inclusion of all Spitzer IRAC infrared imaging ever taken on COSMOS. We find significant improvement in our astrometric reference from 2015 by utilizing Gaia DR1. From this reprocessed data, we perform source detection and photometry for 1 million sources across 2 deg2 of the COSMOS field, using both traditional aperture photometric methods and a new profile-fitting photometric measurement tool we have developed. In addition to a detailed comparison of both methods, we report the achievement of sub-percent accuracy in our derived photometric redshifts at i &amp;lt; 22.5 AB and at 25 &amp;lt; i &amp;lt; 27 of less than 5 per-cent. Encouraged by this result, we present measurements of the deepest wide-field NIR-selected galaxy number counts and discuss several immediate science projects enabled by this work including the galaxy stellar mass and UV luminosity functions as well as constraints on the halo occupation distribution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: A next-generation catalog to explore the 1&lt;z&lt;8 universe</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/caltech2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/caltech2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The COSMOS field has proved to be one of the cornerstone surveys in extragalactic astronomy.
Since our last public catalog in 2015, a wealth of new imaging and spectroscopic data has been
collected in COSMOS. We describe the collection, processing, and analysis of the best available
imaging data in COSMOS over 39 bands and produce a new reference photometric redshift
catalog. Powerful new constraints are made possible from the ultra-deep optical imaging with
Hyper Suprime-Cam, UltraVISTA near-infrared Ks imaging at least 1 magnitude deeper than in
2015, and the inclusion of all Spitzer IRAC infrared imaging ever taken on COSMOS. We find
significant improvement in our astrometric reference from 2015 by utilizing Gaia DR1. From this
reprocessed data, we perform source detection and photometry for 1 million sources across 2 deg2
of the COSMOS field, using both traditional aperture photometric methods and a new profile-fitting
photometric measurement tool we have developed. In addition to a detailed comparison of both
methods, we report the achievement of sub-percent accuracy in our derived photometric redshifts
at i &amp;lt; 22.5 AB and at 25 &amp;lt; i &amp;lt; 27 of less than 5 per-cent. Encouraged by this result, we present
measurements of the deepest wide-field NIR-selected galaxy number counts as well as galaxy
stellar masses with unprecedented statistical confidence out to z~6. Finally, we demonstrate the
power of this ultra-deep multi-wavelength survey with a first look at the cosmological evolution of
galaxy growth via the galaxy stellar mass function with greater constraints than ever before
possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: A panchromatic view of the Universe to z~10 from two complementary catalogs</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/iap2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/iap2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The COSMOS field has proven to be one of the cornerstone surveys in extragalactic astronomy. Since our last public catalog in 2015, a wealth of new imaging and spectroscopic data has been collected in COSMOS. We describe the collection, processing, and analysis of the best available imaging data in COSMOS over 39 bands and produce a new reference photometric redshift catalog. Powerful new constraints are made possible from the ultra-deep optical imaging with Hyper Suprime-Cam, UltraVISTA near-infrared Ks imaging at least 1 magnitude deeper than in 2015, and the inclusion of all Spitzer IRAC infrared imaging ever taken on COSMOS. We find significant improvement in our astrometric reference from 2015 by utilizing Gaia DR1. From this reprocessed data, we perform source detection and photometry for 1 million sources across 2 deg2 of the COSMOS field, using both traditional aperture photometric methods and a new profile-fitting photometric measurement tool we have developed. In addition to a detailed comparison of both methods, we report the achievement of sub-percent accuracy in our derived photometric redshifts at i &amp;lt; 22.5 AB and at 25 &amp;lt; i &amp;lt; 27 of less than 5 per-cent. Encouraged by this result, we present measurements of the deepest wide-field NIR-selected galaxy number counts and discuss three immediate science projects enabled by this work including the galaxy stellar mass and UV luminosity functions as well as constraints on the halo occupation distribution. Important contributions from IAP personnel and facilities in making this work possible will also be highlighted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: A panchromatic view of the Universe to z~10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/aas2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/aas2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>The COSMOS field has proven to be one of the cornerstone surveys in extragalactic astronomy. Since our last public catalog in 2015, a wealth of new imaging and spectroscopic data has been collected in COSMOS. We describe the collection, processing, and analysis of the best available imaging data in COSMOS over 39 bands and produce a new reference photometric redshift catalog. Powerful new constraints are made possible from the ultra-deep optical imaging with Hyper Suprime-Cam, UltraVISTA near-infrared Ks imaging at least 1 magnitude deeper than in 2015, and the inclusion of all Spitzer IRAC infrared imaging ever taken on COSMOS. We find significant improvement in our astrometric reference from 2015 by utilizing Gaia DR1. From this reprocessed data, we perform source detection and photometry for 1 million sources across 2 deg2 of the COSMOS field, using both traditional aperture photometric methods and a new profile-fitting photometric measurement tool we have developed. In addition to a detailed comparison of both methods, we report the achievement of sub-percent accuracy in our derived photometric redshifts at i &amp;lt; 22.5 AB and at 25 &amp;lt; i &amp;lt; 27 of less than 5 per-cent. Encouraged by this result, we present measurements of the deepest wide-field NIR-selected galaxy number counts and discuss several immediate science projects enabled by this work including the galaxy stellar mass and UV luminosity functions as well as constraints on the halo occupation distribution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Directly Probing the Quasar Accretion Disc with Multi-Epoch Photometry</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/yagn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/yagn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>COSMOS2020: a stepping stone for the next generation of galaxy surveys</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/roman2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/talk/roman2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>COSMOS is one of the most valuable fields of observation for extragalactic science, due in part to continued investment in multi-chromatic observation. It is then no surprise that it has played a pivotal role in our understanding of galaxy evolution, especially at early times where sources are too faint to be studied en masse by comparably shallow, wide-field surveys. Now in the decade of groundbreaking optical-NIR facilities such as the Nancy Roman Space Telescope, alongside JWST, LSST, and Euclid, the stage is set to probe deeper into the Universe than ever before. COSMOS is the natural stepping stone in this progressively deeper investigation and has been selected as one of the primary calibration fields for forthcoming surveys. It is for these reasons why we must continue to innovate. We present COSMOS2020, the latest installment of catalogs to map COSMOS, now at unprecedented optical-NIR depths in excess of 28 mags over 2 deg2. A total of 37 bands of photometry are newly extracted for 1M sources using bleeding-edge profile-fitting photometry provided by The Tractor. We find intensely competitive measurements compared to an identical extraction with SExtractor, benchmarked by photometric redshift accuracy below 2% at i &amp;lt; 24. Incredibly, we show that The Tractor provides the incredibly robust high-redshift photometry with remarkably little photometric redshift bias, underscoring the transformative role of profile-fitting photometry in the next generation of galaxy surveys.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>