<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Subaru | John R. Weaver</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/subaru/</link><atom:link href="https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/subaru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Subaru</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 John Weaver</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://astroweaver.github.io/media/icon_hu8e71e1b536ffcaa57bdea0990ac1b238_79891_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Subaru</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/tag/subaru/</link></image><item><title>Beasts in the Bubbles: Remarkably UV-bright Galaxies at z=9-10</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_beasts_fujimoto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_beasts_fujimoto/</guid><description>&lt;p>Subaru/SWIMS | 1.5N | PI - S. Fujimoto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Awarded back-up instrument time on SWIMS)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We propose Keck MOSFIRE J-band spectroscopy for five UV-bright (H =24.5–25.4 mag) novel photometric candidates at z = 9 − 10 from the brand new COSMOS2020 catalogs, now benefitting from homogeneous near-IR and ultra-deep optical coverage that allowed for such identification. All candidates have clear Lyman-break features from Y to H bands, IRAC detection, tight distributions in PDF(z) at z = 9 − 10, the inconsistency with the templates of the stellar and dusty galaxy at lower redshift, and are confirmed at z &amp;gt; 9 with four independent redshift estimates. The volume density of these five candidates is also consistent with the bright-end of the latest UV luminosity function (UVLF) studies at z = 9 − 10. With the proposed observations, we will achieve the following two major goals: 1) confirming the redshift and the power-law nature of the UVLF at z = 9 − 10, and 2) testing if UV-bright galaxies at z = 9 − 10 host AGN via the Nv1243 line. Importantly, our targets are &amp;gt; ×10–20 brighter than the only other source confirmed at z = 9.11. Our targets will provide essential constraints on the bright/massive-end of luminosity/mass function at z &amp;gt; 9 and the CDM scenario for the formation of early galaxies, once at least one of their redshifts are confirmed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep Subaru HSC z-band imaging of the Euclid/JWST/Roman Deep Field</title><link>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_nep_suzuki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astroweaver.github.io/observation/2022_subaru_nep_suzuki/</guid><description>&lt;p>Subaru/HSC | 2N | PI - N. Suzuki&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We request 2 nights of Subaru Hyper-SuprimeCam to complete z-band observations of the largest multi-wavelength (ugriz) field, Hawaii Two-0 (H20), a contiguous survey covering 20 sq. deg area of two primary Euclid Deep Calibration Fields (NEP and CDFS). A total of 30 nights on the Subaru/HSC and 10 nights on the Keck/DEIMOS telescopes were allocated for this program through the Hawaii TAC which has now completed g-, r-, i- band coverage. This proposal is to complete the z-band photometric survey in the NEP field to the desired depth of 26.5 AB. The z-band data are essential for accurate physical parameter measurements of galaxies at 0 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 3 (e.g., photometric redshift and stellar mass) and selection of galaxies at 3 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 6 . These measurements will allow us to study the evolution of massive galaxies to z~6, estimate the properties of their dark matter haloes through clustering measurements, and find rare objects that are re-ionizing the universe. This is a legacy Euclid program.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>